## **Ashley Jackson**

mobile No: 07449813743 E-mail: a.j94@live.co.uk

(Most recent at bottom)

## **Profile:**

A highly enthusiastic and capable worker with experience working in many different environments as a team or solo. Keen to work and to develop new skills over time. Consistently proactive and professional, with good time management and personable skills. Strives to produce good quality work for the company and customer.

## Key skills:

- Good problem solver
- Eager to learn more skills
- Good with practical work as well as paperwork
- loyal and selflessly committed to work as a team or solo
- great time keeping

## **Qualifications:**

#### GCSE's 2010:

- maths (c)
- English (c)
- I.T (c)

## NVQ, 2011:

- level 2 diploma in Engineering maintenance.

#### NVQ, 2016-2020:

- level 2 diploma in Fabrication and welding (semi-skilled).
- level 3 diploma in Fabrication and welding (Skilled), Sheetmetal and platework.

IOSH Health and safety course 2020.

Essential Skills for line managers course 2021.

## **Additional information:**

- Full UK drivers licence including C, C+E, B, B+E and A.
- Forklift licence.
- IPAF licence (Mobile vertical(3a) and Mobile boom(3b)).

#### Career history:

## School leaver (High School)

(Feb 2010)

## GCSE's:

- maths (c)
- English (c)
- I.T (c)

## NatWest bank PLC (Cashier)

(Mar 2010- Nov 2010)

## Further Information:

- Dealt with personal records through a computer programme and processed large amounts of money daily.
- Used personable skills to help hundreds of people on a daily basis to resolve their problems and keep the customer happy.
- kept good time keeping and was consistently loyal to colleagues and customers throughout the workplace.

## British Army, Royal Engineer, (Fitter General) (Nov 2010– Apr 2016)

NVQ, 2011: level 2 diploma in Engineering maintenance.

## Skills achieved:

- Maintenance and repairing of diesel and petrol engines.
- Vehicle wiring and fault finding.
- Hydraulic systems maintenance and repair.
- Fuel systems maintenance and repair.
- · Water pump systems maintenance and repair.
- Fabrication and welding.
- Engineers' drawings using pattern development.

#### Further information:

- Maintained and serviced mechanical equipment monthly to allow a good workflow within the organisation.
- Complete paperwork on the relevant task to show it has been done properly and to a good standard while organising paperwork into records for future references.
- Complete store checks to keep workflow active by allowing a constant supply of parts and tools to get jobs done quick and easy and on time.
- Completed medical/first aid training.
- Stuck to strict deadlines and timings throughout time served.

## BJ Stainless Fabrications, Fabricator (Family-owned business)

(Apr 2016- Mar 2021)

## NVQ, 2016-2020:

- level 2 diploma in Fabrication and welding (semi-skilled)
- level 3 diploma in Fabrication and welding (Skilled), Sheetmetal and platework. Skills Achieved:
  - High standard of fabrication using MMA, MIG and TIG. This includes MIG and TIG weld procedures and codes for structural parts.

- Pattern development to make items such as square to rounds, lobster back piping out of sheet metal etc...
- Reading engineer/assembly drawings.
- Cutting using Oxy Acetylene, Plasma, guillotines, band saws, handheld grinders etc...
- Operating 150 tonne pressing machine to produce items to fine tolerances.
- Using rolling machines for tube and sheet/plate.
- Polishing of products ranging from a dull polish finish to mirror polish depending on customer requirements.
- Use of various fasteners and fixing to produce a finished item.

## Further Information:

- Worked with various materials including mild steel, 304/316 stainless, aluminium, brass, copper, bronze etc...
- Produced jobs ranging from bespoke handrails and gates, structural beam work for buildings, bespoke furniture, parts for conveyor machines, small- and large-scale signage, therapy pools and much more.
- All jobs were completed from start to finish including installations across the UK.

# BJS Fabrications & BJS powder coating, Co-Ordinator(Mar 2021- July 2023) (Family-owned business)

## Skills Achieved:

- Managing and co-ordinating the production of a large quantity of orders.
- Dealing with high profile customers such as Naughtone and Herman Miller.
- Quoting the fabrication and powder coating of products.
- Processing orders and purchases using Sage accounts.
- Purchasing the correct materials required for each job.
- Guiding fabricators through various production process to meet customer requirements and ensuring deadlines/delivery dates are met.

#### Further Information:

- Helping customers develop products and solve faults with products.
- Created a catalogue price list via Excel showing break down of product costs.
- Created a product database using Sage accounts to streamline customer orders and supplier purchases.
- Created stock spread sheets using Excel to control company spending and speed up fabrication processes.
- Also still fabricate work with fabricators when required to prevent work falling behind schedule.
- Powder coating products and packaging ready for delivery to customers.
- Producing of risk assessments for various working scenarios to ensure staff are working safely in accordance with ISO's the companies hold.
- Undertake shop health and safety briefings with employees to prevent accidents within the workplace.

## (July 2023 - Present)

I have always been facinated with technology and what we as a civilisation can achieve with such applications therefore on my departure of my previouse role I had decided to re-trade to follow a path I believe is right for me. Since July I have been stydying front-end development using w3 schools, free code camp, Udemy, youtube, google and other platforms. In October I started a bootcamp with The Coders Guild to help push closer towards working in the tech industry.

## Skills Achieved:

- HTML(Semantic) to structure and create webpages.
- CSS to style the HTML documents.
- Bootstrap CDN's and framworks.
- Psuedocode for projects.
- JavaScript(EcmaScript) using functions, loops, arrays, objects, ..., aswell as making HTML documents responsive.
- GIThub workflows.
- Source controle using GIT commands.
- Static site generators(i.e- 11Ty).
- Able to navigate and use Visual Studio code(VS code).

## Further Information:

- Dedicated to learn new skills including other coding languages, different ways to complete tasks and problems to become a better developer.
- Have a strong drive and desire to push myself through each stage of learing.
- Don't give up on a problem until its solved.